# William D. Vest iii

Bowling Green, KY 42101 (270) 282-9088 • tsukasasan@hotmail.com





in /in/william-d-vest 🔰 @ vested\_tech 🕟 github.com/AD-6Skyraider 🔐 hashnode.com/@AD-6SkyRaider

### **SUMMARY**

Motivated professional with 20+ years management/supervisor experience. Earning promotions to such posts in nearly every position I've held since I was 17 years old. I was able to make such accomplishments by valuing a second-to-none work ethic. A dedication to the job and by earning the respect of my superiors and peers by being a leader. I accomplished this by leading by example. Doing the difficult and decidedly unglamorous tasks required by the job. These skills were taught to me by my father (a drill sergeant) and first employer (a retired Navy Chef) then built on and cemented with experience. These skills, married to my personality and added to my interests, hobbies and crafts, have culminated in a perfect passion for computer programming and web design.

Web Development Skills								
<b>&gt;</b>	Microsoft Office	>	Bootstrap	>	SQL			
>	365 HTML	<₽	JavaScript	>	JQuery			
<b>&gt;</b>	Chrome Dev Tools	>	Git React	<∤>	SEO			
<b>&gt;</b>	CSS	>	Node.js					
<b>〈</b> 〉	SASS	<b>\(\frac{\partial}{2}\)</b>	MongoDB					

Additional Skills: I'm proficient in many office systems/machines. Microsoft or Apple, phone systems, copiers, OFFICE Suite etc. in addition to formatting a myriad of communication letters and emails and facilitating employee meetings and meetings with clients.

## **EXPERIENCE**

W	<u>ork</u>	Н	is	tor	V

	<u>m orre i invery</u>	
Route Sales Manager	Williams Sausage Company Inc.	2019 - 2020
Shift Lead/Recovery Coach	Stepworks Recovery Center	2017 - 2018
Park Ranger/Parks & Rec.	City of Bowling Green	2014 - 2018
Family/Victim Advocate	SpringHaven Domestic Violence Program	2011 - 2012
Mental Health Associate	Lincoln Trail Behavioral Health	2008 - 2011
Mental Health Associate	Spectrum Care Academy	2005 - 2007
Youth Counselor/Case Manager	Presbyterian Child Welfare Agency	2000 - 2004

#### Additional Involvement

Instructor - Life Space Crisis Intervention Founder Non-Traditional Student Alliance Officer - Young Professionals of Hardin County Owner & Director - Vested Theatre Company Academic Honors Award - Fine Arts

Founder & President - Ester Mae Foundation Officer – University Greek and Roman Classics Club Member - The Toy Box Players (Children's Theater) Participant -Cardboard Nation, A Homeless Experience Board Member - Diverse City

## **EDUCATION**

Lanier Technical College - Oakwood, GA

Business Management

Elizabethtown Community & Technical -Elizabethtown, KY - Anthropology/Psychology

**Southern Utah University** – Cedar City, UT

Archaeology Field School

Western Kentucky University – Bowling Green, KY

History & Creative Writing

Commonwealth Coders - Web Development Academy

Full Stack Web Development

Udemy - Git/Github, Complete Web Dev Program (under Colt Steele and Angela Yu), Python Bootcamp

**Professional Certifications** First Aid/CPR - Smith Driving System – Life Space Crisis Intervention